Mansi Kamlesh Bhatt

Contact: +91 9920481969; Email: mansi.soni1988@gmail.com; Date of Birth: 7th September, 1988

Ahmedabad, India - 382481.

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Human Resource Manager / HRBP professional offering 12.6 years' experience in achieving positive results for multiple companies. Organized planner with excellent team leadership and program management abilities. Excellent organizational and time management skills coupled with task prioritization. Looking forward to work with your esteemed organization to provide end to end HR support.

SUMMARY OF SKILLS

- Operational Expertise
- Flexible and Adaptable
- MS Office, HRMS & other HR software applications
- Multitasking Abilities
- Training and Development
- Excellent Communication and interpersonal skills
- Teamwork and Collaboration
- Critical Thinking
- Decision-Making
- Planning and Coordination
- Self-Motivated

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Radix Software Services Pvt. Ltd. (Radixweb) (Ahmedabad)

DEC 2019 - CURRENT

Assistant Manager - HR

- Worked with managers to achieve compliance with organizational policies, providing clarifying information and recommending necessary changes.
- Enhanced team workflows and employee job satisfaction by coordinating communication between managers and employees
- Planning of Events, Rewards & Recognition and Certification activities
- Manage and execute various HR processes and programs, such as onboarding, performance management, employee development, benefits administration, employee off boarding (exit process), and policy implementation for a strength of 700+ employees. Maintain accurate HR records and generate relevant reports as needed.
- Created and implemented forward-thinking initiatives to improve employee engagement. Organize and participate in teambuilding activities, events, and employee recognition programs.
- Discovered and resolved complex employee issues that affected management and business decisions
- Facilitated successful enforcement to maintain operational compliance and to manage smooth flow of day-to-day HR operational activities
- Employee Relations: Serve as the primary point of contact for employees regarding HR-related matters, including
 grievances, conflicts, and performance issues. Provide guidance, counseling, and support to managers and employees,
 ensuring fair and consistent application of policies and procedures.
- Identified and implemented appropriate strategies to increase employee satisfaction and retention
- Coordinated technical training and personal development sessions for employees at all levels
- Updated training processes by reviewing existing documentation, leveraging feedback from associates
- Liaised between multiple business divisions to improve communications
- Reduced process gaps while supervising employees to achieve optimal productivity
- Managed internal MIS and database management systems

ROLTA INDIA LTD. (Mumbai)

Senior Support Officer - HR

- Talent Acquisition, Bulk Hiring, Contract Hiring
- HR Operations, End to end hiring, On Boarding process, Induction
- Data Management, Data Operations, Documentation, Stakeholder Management
- Skilled at working independently and collaboratively in a team environment
- Managed time efficiently in order to complete all tasks within deadlines
- Tracking of various reports and daily MIS to ensure operational efficiency

CINESTAAN DIGITAL PVT. LTD. (Mumbai)

DEC 2018 - FEB 2019

Assistant Manager – People & Culture

- Mentored team members to enhance professional development and accountability in workplace. Handled end-2-end onboarding process and off boarding process
- Supervised day-to-day operations to meet performance, quality and service expectations
- Recruited, interviewed and hired employees and implemented mentoring program to promote positive feedback and engagement
- Cultivated positive rapport with fellow employees to boost company morale and promote employee retention
- Controlled resources and assets for department activities to comply with industry standards and government regulations
- Created and implemented forward-thinking initiatives to improve employee engagement
- Discovered and resolved complex employee issues that affected management and business decisions. Took charge of stakeholder management
- Evaluated employee performance and conveyed constructive feedback to improve skills
- Defined clear targets and objectives and communicated to other team members
- Handled the entire process of statutory compliances

TEAM LEASE SERVICES LTD. (Mumbai)

JAN 2015 - DEC 2015

Senior Career Consultant

- Identified and sourced qualified candidates for open positions to meet organizational needs
- Managed recruitment process to keep candidates informed about application status and meet organizational recruitment
- Screened and interviewed candidates to evaluate potential employees' qualifications
- Networked and built relationships with potential candidates and industry professionals to identify potential candidates, stay informed about industry trends and gain insight into skills and qualifications in demand

GREEN ROOTZ MANPOWER (Mumbai)

MAR 2013 - JAN 2015

Assistant Manager Recruitment - HR

- Managed end-2-end recruitment activities
- Built strong relationships with internal and external candidates to ensure an excellent hiring experience
- Conducted phone interviews to assess applicant's relevant knowledge, skills, experience and aptitudes
- Advertised job opportunities on social media platforms and job boards
- Conducted reference checks, background screening and other pre-employment checks to verify information on applicant's resume
- Coordinated schedules to arrange management interviews with applicants
- Evaluated strengths and weaknesses of candidates through effective screening processes
- Studied job descriptions and qualifications to determine applicant requirements
- Collaborated with hiring managers to understand job requirements and expectations
- Developed recruiting strategies to identify qualified candidates and build network
- Skilled at working independently and collaboratively in a team environment
- Self-motivated, with a strong sense of personal responsibility
- Proven ability to learn quickly and adapt to new situations

JAN 2016 - SEP 2018

Senior Associate Advisor

- Built strong relationships with internal and external candidates to ensure an excellent hiring experience
- Conducted phone interviews to assess applicant's relevant knowledge, skills, experience and aptitudes
- Advertised job opportunities on social media platforms and job sites
- Conducted reference checks, background screening and other pre-employment checks to verify information on applicant's resume
- Coordinated schedules to arrange management interviews with applicants
- Evaluated strengths and weaknesses of candidates through effective screening processes
- Studied job descriptions and qualifications to determine applicant requirements
- Collaborated with hiring managers to understand job requirements and expectations
- Developed recruiting strategies to identify qualified candidates and build network
- Skilled at working independently and collaboratively in a team environment

EDUCATIONAL CREDENTIALS

M.B.A (HR) - 2015

Jamnalal Bajaj Institute of management Studies (JBIMS)

M.COM (Business Management) - 2011

Mumbai University

B.COM (Commerce) - 2009

Mithibai College of Commerce & Economics – First Class

H.S.C (Commerce) - 2006

Mumbai Maharashtra State Board – First Class

S.S.C - 2004

Mumbai Maharashtra State Board - Distinction Grade

Computer Proficiency

MS-Office (Excel / Word / Power point) & Outlook

STRENGTHS

- Team player, positive attitude, convincing ability, patience, good listener and reliable
- Maximum commitments & dedication towards work accepted
- Honesty & Dignity towards my work
- Willingness to learn more, self-motivated, result oriented
- Negotiation skills, problem solving skills
- High level of integrity and the ability to maintain confidentiality

INTEREST AREAS: Travelling, Watching motivational videos, Strong believer in Law of Attraction

DECLARATION: I hereby declare that all the information given above is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

REFERENCES: To be provided upon request.